<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>virtualization on Another blog</title>
    <link>https://cychong47.github.io/tags/virtualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in virtualization on Another blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:03:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cychong47.github.io/tags/virtualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Astri vRAN</title>
      <link>https://cychong47.github.io/post/2018/astri-vran/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:03:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cychong47.github.io/post/2018/astri-vran/</guid>
      <description>Toward 5G RAN virtualization by Intel and Astri
http://astri.oeg
Flexible architecture Modular PHY processing architectures  PDCP Split MAC/PHY Split - HARQ processing in RRU(How???) Lower PHY Split - High FB overhead but smallest packet latency.  Good for JT and JR for COMP Good for Massive MIMO and Ultra low-latency communication(Why?)   FAPI based MAC/PHY communication  L1 adaptation layer for MAC/PHY split (and Lower PHY Split?)    MAC/PHY split in one CPU  MAC/PHY split in one machine but netrwork based MAC/PHY communication over OVS   Virtual Cell  A group of physical cells form a Virtual Cell which does not require HO between the physical cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CISCO Cloud Service Platform 2100</title>
      <link>https://cychong47.github.io/post/2015/cisco-cloud-service-platform-2100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 14:24:35 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cychong47.github.io/post/2015/cisco-cloud-service-platform-2100/</guid>
      <description>Data sheet (PDF)
 Some Cisco virtual network services that use the DPDK include Cisco Cloud Services Router (CSR) 1000V, Cisco Virtual Mobile Packet Core software, and Cisco IOS® XR 9000v virtual router. Supporte CISCO appliances  Cisco Cloud Services Router (CSR) 1000V virtual router Cisco Virtual Adaptive Security Appliance (ASAv) Cisco Prime™ Data Center Network Manager (DCNM) Cisco Virtual Network Analysis Module (vNAM) Cisco Virtual Security Gateway (VSG) for Cisco Nexus® 1000V Switch deployments Cisco Virtual Supervisor Module (VSM) for Cisco Nexus 1000V Switch deployments   1U 2 CPU, each has 8 core Ivy Bridge(E5-2630 v3) REST API It uses REST API and NETCONF protocol for north-bound management and orchestration (MANO) tools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>